The game has changed.
TRON: Legacy is a adventure, action, science fiction
film directed by Joseph Kosinski.
Sam Flynn, the tech-savvy and daring son of Kevin Flynn, investigates
his father's disappearance and is pulled into The Grid.
With the help of a mysterious program named Quorra, Sam quests to stop
evil dictator Clu from crossing into the real world.
Sam Flynn, played by Garrett Hedlund.
Quorra, played by Olivia Wilde.
Kevin Flynn / Clu, played by Jeff Bridges.
Alan Bradley / Tron, played by Bruce Boxleitner.
Jarvis, played by James Frain.
Gem, played by Beau Garrett.
Tron: Legacy is a 2010 American science fiction action film directed by
Joseph Kosinski, and written by Adam Horowitz and Edward Kitsis.
It is the second installment in the Tron series and a sequel to Tron (1982).
The film stars Jeff Bridges, Garrett Hedlund, Olivia
Wilde, Bruce Boxleitner, and Michael Sheen.
The story follows Kevin Flynn's adult son Sam, who responds to a message from his long-lost father and is transported into a virtual reality
called "the Grid", where Sam, his father, and the algorithm Quorra must stop the malevolent program Clu from invading the real world.
Interest in creating a sequel to Tron arose after
the film garnered a cult following.
After much speculation, Walt Disney Pictures began a concerted effort in 2005 to devise a
sequel, with the hiring of Brian Klugman and Lee Sternthal as writers.
Kosinski was recruited as director two years later.
As he was not optimistic about Disney's The Matrix-esque approach to the film, Kosinski filmed a concept trailer, which
he used to conceptualize the universe of Tron: Legacy and convince the studio to greenlight the film.
Principal photography took place in Vancouver over 67 days, in
and around the city's central business district.
Most sequences were shot in 3D and ten companies were
involved with the extensive visual effects work.
Chroma keying and other techniques were used to
allow more freedom in creating effects.
Daft Punk composed the musical score, incorporating their
trademark electronic music with orchestral sounds.
Tron: Legacy premiered in Tokyo on November 30, 2010, and was released in the
United States on December 17, by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
Disney vigorously promoted the film across multiple media platforms, including
merchandising, consumer products, theme parks, and advertising.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and was a commercial
success, grossing $410 million against a $170 million budget.
The film was nominated for Best Sound Editing at the 83rd Academy Awards.
Like its predecessor, Tron: Legacy has been
described as a cult film since its release.
A further sequel, Tron: Ares, was released in 2025.
The film explores themes of artificial intelligence (a.i.),
computer program, secret identity, dystopia, simulation.
The tone is thought_provoking.